<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2020-07-02T00:43:30+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jiawei Zhan</title><subtitle>&quot;Best Jekyll Theme by a Mile&quot;. **Hydejack** is your presence on the web, featuring a blog, portfolio, and resume.
</subtitle><author><name>Jiawei Zhan</name><email>jiaweiz@uchicago.edu</email></author><entry><title type="html">New paper “Ogre: A Python package for molecular crystal surface generation with applications to surface energy and crystal habit prediction” is published and selected as JCP Emerging Investigators Special Collection</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/2020-06-26-Ogre-published/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New paper &lt;em&gt;&quot;Ogre:&amp;nbsp;A Python package for molecular crystal surface generation with applications to surface energy and crystal habit prediction&quot;&lt;/em&gt; is published and selected as JCP Emerging Investigators Special Collection" /><published>2020-06-26T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-06-26T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/Ogre-published</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/2020-06-26-Ogre-published/">&lt;p&gt;I’m very glad to announce that our paper &lt;em&gt;Ogre&lt;/em&gt; is published online and selected to become a part of JCP Emerging Investigators Special Collection. 
This paper partially represent the efforts we have made on surface generatons.
We want to write a tool to cleave slabs and predict the optimized
structure of interfaces. And this paper contains the first step. In this paper, we present Ogre, 
an open-source code for generating molecular crystal surface slabs based on
graphic molecular representations. Moreover, we utilize Ogre to carry out
quantum-chemistry calculation and crystal habit prediction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the subsequent research, we will use Ogre to cleave slabs and predict
optimized interfaces of two slabs via Monte-Carlo Methods and machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;font size=&quot;5&quot;&gt;Reference:&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ogre: A Python package for molecular crystal surface generation with applications to surface energy and crystal habit prediction&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;color:gray&quot;&gt; &lt;font size=&quot;3&quot;&gt;Shuyang Yang, Imanuel Bier, Wen Wen, &lt;span style=&quot;color:black&quot;&gt;Jiawei Zhan&lt;/span&gt;, Saeed Moayedpour, and Noa Marom&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;color:rgb(79,177,186);font-weight:bold&quot;&gt; &lt;font size=&quot;3&quot;&gt;J. Chem. Phys. 152, 244122 (2020)&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;font size=&quot;3&quot;&gt;/&lt;/font&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acssuschemeng.0c01151&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:rgb(79,177,186)&quot;&gt; &lt;font size=&quot;3&quot;&gt;AIP&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;font size=&quot;3&quot;&gt;/&lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.noamarom.com/software/ogre/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:rgb(79,177,186)&quot;&gt; &lt;font size=&quot;3&quot;&gt;Project Page&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jiawei Zhan</name><email>jiaweiz@uchicago.edu</email></author><summary type="html">I’m very glad to announce that our paper Ogre is published online and selected to become a part of JCP Emerging Investigators Special Collection. This paper partially represent the efforts we have made on surface generatons. We want to write a tool to cleave slabs and predict the optimized structure of interfaces. And this paper contains the first step. In this paper, we present Ogre, an open-source code for generating molecular crystal surface slabs based on graphic molecular representations. Moreover, we utilize Ogre to carry out quantum-chemistry calculation and crystal habit prediction.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Our new paper “Potassium-Doped g-C3N4 Achieving Efficient Visible-Light-Driven CO2 Reduction” is published on ACS Sustainable Chem. Eng.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/2020-05-13-gC3N4-published/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Our new paper &lt;em&gt;&quot;Potassium-Doped g-C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Achieving Efficient Visible-Light-Driven CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction&quot;&lt;/em&gt; is published on ACS Sustainable Chem. Eng." /><published>2020-05-13T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-05-13T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/gC3N4-published</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/2020-05-13-gC3N4-published/">&lt;p&gt;I’m very happy to anounce that our paper is finally published after one year of
theoretical computations and experiments. In this paper, we report a new study on 
the potassium-doped g-C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; (K-CN) being used for CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; reduction irradiated by visible light. 
And Our work further validates the importance of inhibiting e&lt;sup&gt;–&lt;/sup&gt;/h&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; recombination 
in improving solar energy conversion efficiency while also bringing hope for efficient solar fuel production using g-C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;font size=&quot;5&quot;&gt;Reference:&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Potassium-Doped g-C3N4 Achieving Efficient Visible-Light-Driven CO2 Reduction&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;color:gray&quot;&gt; &lt;font size=&quot;3&quot;&gt;Shuhui Wang, &lt;span style=&quot;color:black&quot;&gt;Jiawei Zhan&lt;/span&gt;, Kui Chen, Asad Ali, Linghui Zeng, He Zhao, Wanglai Hu*, Lixin Zhu*, and Xiaoliang Xu*&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;color:rgb(79,177,186);font-weight:bold&quot;&gt; &lt;font size=&quot;3&quot;&gt;ACS Sustainable Chem. Eng. 2020, 8, 22, 8214–8222&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;font size=&quot;3&quot;&gt;/&lt;/font&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acssuschemeng.0c01151&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:rgb(79,177,186)&quot;&gt; &lt;font size=&quot;3&quot;&gt;ACS Publication&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jiawei Zhan</name><email>jiaweiz@uchicago.edu</email></author><summary type="html">I’m very happy to anounce that our paper is finally published after one year of theoretical computations and experiments. In this paper, we report a new study on the potassium-doped g-C3N4 (K-CN) being used for CO2 reduction irradiated by visible light. And Our work further validates the importance of inhibiting e–/h+ recombination in improving solar energy conversion efficiency while also bringing hope for efficient solar fuel production using g-C3N4.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Introducing My Personal Website</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/2020-01-01-generate-homepage/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introducing My Personal Website" /><published>2020-01-01T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-01-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/generate-homepage</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/2020-01-01-generate-homepage/">&lt;p&gt;This is my new personal website. It will witness my researches and my progress
duing the doctoral study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;font size=&quot;10&quot;&gt;Cheers!&lt;/font&gt;</content><author><name>Jiawei Zhan</name><email>jiaweiz@uchicago.edu</email></author><summary type="html">This is my new personal website. It will witness my researches and my progress duing the doctoral study.</summary></entry></feed>